uh so uh today's lecture is on Behavior
cloning specifically on diffusion
policies I'm sorry I'm not able to do
this in person I was on a trip and I
caught a cold so I'm going to do only a
1H hour lecture and on zoom and I'll
give you some reading material or
watching material for the next hour so
what's the topic of Interest the topic
of interest to us is uh is the following
it's this area called robot learning
from demonstration and it's been around
forever uh it's uh it was uh in fact the
earliest robots had uh these ideas were
in use then so I've got I here's the
abstract of a paper recent review paper
by these folks and they have the
statement in the context of Robotics and
automation learning from demonstration
is the Paradigm in which robot acquiring
new skills by learning to imitate an
expert and then they abbreviate this as
lft learning from
demonstration so the choice of lft over
other robot learning methods is
compelling when ideal Behavior can be
neither easily scripted as is done in
traditional robot programming nor easily
defined as an optimization problem but
can be
demonstrated so uh let's uh look at the
variations on this theme so here is the
first first one it's called kinesthetic
teaching and this goes back to the
earliest days of Robotics so basically
what you do is you make the robot go
through the
movements and uh and as the and then you
just record that trajectory and then you
replay it so an example of when this
might work is for example you want to
have a robot do a painting task and you
just make it go through the movements
and then it just replays it repeatedly
in a factory
setting second example
is uh T operation so here this is B in
the middle so what do you see here here
there's a person with some
controller and what he or she is trying
to do is to make the robot go through
certain motions while observing the
robot to the task so you might
essentially be controlling the joints of
the robot so that the robot picks up an
object moves it around what have you so
this is teleoperation now
teleoperation has existed for a very
long time in the early days it was used
basically for working in hazardous
environments so in a hazardous
environment you have a robot let's say
in a nuclear reactor kind of situation
and then there's a person working uh
remotely and they are
manipulating uh the robot in this remote
way in a safe environment and then of
course the uh the robot is is going
through exactly the same motions that
the human is going through now in this
process you can collect
trajectories and then subsequently you
can use those trajectories in a form of
supervised learning to uh to train a new
policy and and that's going to be the
bulk of today's lecture okay uh then
approach C is passive observation and
this is what I call genuine imitation
learning so normally
how do how do children
learn uh from observation so there isn't
an adult who's controlling their brain
to make them go through the entire
sequence of actions I mean that's the
teleoperation thing but that's not what
we we do not t operate our children what
we do is we might show them a task for
example we might show them how we uh
make an omelet right or assemble some
Lego uh pieces together and the child
observes what we are doing and then uh
learns from that so this is sometimes
called imitation learning because
children have a strong urge to imitate
now this is a harder version of the
problem than what you saw in A and B
because you do not uh have the same body
so so you do not have access to the full
state right the uh the child who's
imitating the parent doesn't have access
to the full State uh like what is what
are the mental uh commands being issued
by the parent and so on and so forth so
it's an incomplete knowledge that you
have to make use of and then there is a
shift in the embodiment because the
person's body is not the same as the
child's body or the person's body is not
the same as the robots body so all this
makes it more complicated the advantage
of this approach is that with this you
have lots and lots of data because you
can take all the 156 million hours of
video on YouTube for example and use
that for training a robot so we we will
study this approach but in the next
lecture okay uh so this is uh what we'll
call Visual limitation so today's
lecture is primarily about B and this
has become a very popular approach in
the last few years and one of the
reasons is that there's been uh kind of
a breakthrough called diffusion policy
which has enabled a very good machinery
for taking a lot of robot uh
trajectories collected by T operation
and then uh use that to train a policy
so it's a supervised learning setup
supervised learning we know works very
effectively for example in tasks like
computer vision so this is basically
trading converting the task of uh robot
training uh training a robot to do
manipulation a supervised learning
task any question so
far and uh in the last lecture we were
talking about reinforcement learning so
there the setup is that you specify the
task by some kind of a objective
function or cost function and then
reinforcement learning is just a way to
find an uh to optimize it to find policy
which optimizes that so there the the
the basic Insight is that the
specification of the task is through a
cost function in t operation the
specification or task is just copy the
sequence that humans did at training
time so it's a much easier way to
specify a
task okay so uh I'll talk about this
paper diffusion policy this is from
shuran songs group uh they were she was
originally at Colombia and then she has
moved to Stanford and there are a couple
of papers the first one is RSS 2023 and
the second one is at igr 2024 so this
later paper is in collaboration with
people at Toyota Research Institute and
then they took this approach and applied
it to a a lot more tasks so but the core
ideas are there in the in the first
paper so uh what I'm going to do is uh
to give you a little flavor of this by
uh just playing uh a video but first uh
let me uh let me go to the next slide so
this slide is like the abstract of this
paper so these are the claims of Fame uh
so diffusion policy a new way of
generating robot Behavior by
representing a robots visual motor
policy is a conditional Den noising
diffusion process so blah blah blah
they're testing it on a variety of
different manipulation tasks and they
find that it it does much better than
the the various Alternatives so what I'm
going to do is I'm going to I found a
lecture on uh YouTube from the authors
of this approach and I'll play a little
bit of that because that has
demonstrations of what tasks it can
do thanks Alex so much uh for
introducing me uh to the audience and
thanks for inviting me
to is a visual motor policy that we can
deploy to our robots therefore
regardless of how the policy is trained
if the representation of the policy
itself is not expressive enough you can
easily bottleneck all of the
approaches today I like to convince you
that with sufficiently powerful policy
representation even the simplest
learning paradigms like Behavior cloning
can work very
well uh and here are some examples of
Def policy train on a variety of path
directly from pixels and you can observe
some interesting behaviors for example
recovery from failure and robustness
against perturbations and
occlusions uh so what is div policy I
think many of you might be familiar with
the fusure model for image generation uh
here we're using a similar idea to
generate robot actions so uh in theut
model well like for example like like
mid Journey uh it's a text condition
image generation model so the input is
uh text uh and then uh the output is uh
an image where and then the image is
generated using a diffusion process and
in our case uh policiy input is image
and the polies output is a sequence of
actions that is generated being
generated using D
model and here uh in the bottom we have
an example that's shown as a sequence of
2D antifactor positions which is the
action space for this task uh it's a
mirror of the simulation pushy task and
but the method is can generalized to
pretty much any dimension of degree
freedom for your
robot yeah so concretely we start with G
noise and then neuron network is learned
a train to predict the gradient of
action to remove the noise condition on
robot's visual observation after a few
of these dening steps it will give us a
clean and executable action trajectory
and the whole Den noising process is a
policy representation it repeats at two
Herz resulting in a reactive closeable
Behavior Uh so with this simple
formulation defion policy is able to
simultaneously address a number of
challenges in policy learning and today
I'll highlight three of
them first is the capability of res
representing action
multimodality uh which in this scenario
uh there are multiple valid actions for
the same observation for example uh on
the left we have this uh push T example
the goal is for the blue dot is like the
robot and then uh the goal is to push
this gray T into this green area so at
this exact moment there are two
perfectly equally valid uh actions to
take one is to go around the top of the
PT and push it another one is go from
the bottom to push it in fact both of
these moles exist in our training data
and for a human demonstration
depending our mood we we might randomly
pick one of one on the top or one on the
bottom and we can imagine that if both
both of these uh uh data exist in the
training data set if your polish
representation is a function then it
will get very confused uh which is
actually really the the Assumption of a
lot of the prior Behavior cloning or
polic representations so as we all know
uh your networks fe4 new Networks as
universal function approximator so it's
a really powerful representing function
but it can also only represent functions
and here the difference is that now what
we want to represent is a bodal
distribution instead of a function given
one input sometimes we want to go one on
one way sometimes we want to go the
other way and if if we represent it as a
function and let's say if we train with
something like L2 L then the policy will
learn to take the average between to
minimize the distance to all data point
as a result it'll learn the average of
all datas uh and it will probably go
through the middle imagine you're
driving a car uh you're trying to avoid
a tree uh then if you do action
regression then like it it will go
straight to through the tree and then
crash uh similarly uh so I guess one of
the surprising thing is that this action
modality of course I can we can
construct this very specific case where
action multimodality is important uh but
it's actually surprisingly common and my
observation is that a lot of these uh
action modality ma multim modality comes
from pausing behavior for example in the
middle here is the real version of the
pushy task the task is not only to push
this T into the center region but also
after it is done the robot is the side
now I'm done I need to go to the upper
right there's a circle I draw on table
that's the exit
location and you can imagine there there
are many instances during this episode
where it's the some the t is somewhere
there somewhat inside and some but so
like anytime the policy can exit but
also you can just spend a little bit
more time keep refining the post of the
object and humans sometimes you know
depending whether I'm TI or not make
very different decision at at different
point of whether this is good good
enough or not and pretty much that
creates a huge amount action modality
action multimodality and U if you if you
don't use a representation for example
like defusion policy then the policy
will struggle
uh so previous method uh often attempts
to approximate this multimodal
distributions with categorical
distributions we mixure of
cions cion you pick and then you're
also instead of a single step which
turns out to be critical to ensure
temporal consistency among output
actions uh and finally diffusion policy
is also quite stable to train which is
also essential uh for robot
especi this stability is especially
compared against energy based models
which I'll talk about later and this
because for robotics packpoint selection
often requires very expensive real world
evaluation it's not a metric that you
can log during training um so if if if
you have to select if if for example the
model is EAS to overtrain either over
fit or if the model is will easily
diverge you might not even know during
training and then you have to run every
single checkpoint on the robot to figure
out which is good that will be a very
tedious and very errorr
process so uh
so I'm I'm I want to stop that uh video
and I want to get back to my
slides okay
so uh What uh what you learned so far
was uh the value of uh of of the
so-called uh diffusion policy uh which
is a way to uh combine a lot of uh
demonstrations so you collect a lot of
daily operation demonstrations and then
you make them uh uh and then you you
sort of put them all together into this
diffusion policy so I uh so it's a
particular application of these
diffusion mod based uh generative
modeling so what I'm going to do in the
rest of the lecture is to actually give
you the the general some insight into
the general theory and then the
diffusion policy is just a special case
of this so it's a special case of
diffusion models and in specifically
conditioned diffusion models and the
conditioning here is on the observation
so we must try to understand the the
general uh the general approach Ro first
and uh in the in the lecture that I
played like 5 minutes 10 minutes
worth I mean that was kind of gloss
because it was assumed that the reader
knows that so but this is what I'm going
to focus in the rest of my lecture and
what I've got here are slides from a
tutorial on diffusion modeling which was
presented at cvpr uh year A couple of
years ago and uh so I'm going to take
you through that
okay so so what's the problem we are
trying to study so this is the area of
uh what's called generative modeling and
uh the concept of generative modeling is
the following you're trying to find a
probability distribution from which you
can sample so for example you want to
have a probability distribution over the
space of all
images so uh so this is what is uh
indicated here by this this person with
this neural network work in his head and
from that uh from that model what you
can do is sample so so you can generate
one sample you might get a cat or you
generate another sample you might get a
dog a third sample you might get
Jennifer Aniston and so on so imagine
that there is a space of all possible
images and then there is a probability
distribution over all spaces because if
you think of the set of functions
from uh from uh say let's say if you
consider say a a a 4x4 image right so a
4x4 image has 16 pixels now if each
pixel can take uh one of 256 values then
you have 256 to the^ 16 so these are the
set of possible images that there are
but this this is not the set of natural
images natural images are very very
spars in this set of all possible images
and what you want is this uh this
function this probability density
function over the set of natural images
from which you can sample and this
function is very very important and very
useful because when you consider
conditional version of it you can you
can use it for Den noising you can use
it for Generation you can solve it for
for like a a a huge variety of problems
and uh so this whole area of generative
modeling which is uh finding the
probability distribution over let's say
the set of images is is an exciting area
and one in which a lot of progress has
been made uh in in the early ERA this
was uh the area was dominated by Gans
and Gans had lots of problems and I
don't want to go into those but today uh
I would say
that there are uh then today these
denoising diffusion models seem to be
winning this battle uh at least in the
context of images in the context of of
uh language uh Auto regressive models
those are also generative models so they
they seem to be popular there uh
theoretically very important idea is
that of variational
autoencoders which in fact if you want
to understand the the of diffusion
models you have to go back to
understanding a little bit of the theory
of these so-called vas variational
autoencoders and let's see how far I go
in the next half hour but I'll give you
references so you can read up and uh
understand this
better so uh so let's first go through
some examples of what diffusion models
can do so I'm going to use examples of
uh images but I mean all these ideas
just exactly transfer over to the to the
setting of
policies okay so so these are just
examples of images that can be produced
by these diffusion models so these
images can be uh we can do condition
generation so for example I can
condition by some text like lion or
tiger or an astronaut on a bicycle and
uh then you you you synthesize the image
conditioned on this text and that's
that's how these uh models like Di and
images and so forth operate uh in the
context of Robotics what are we going to
do the conditioning is on going to be on
the basis of observations so the
observation might be some image
observation for example or some
proprioceptive
observation okay so these are some
examples of uh text to image
generation uh okay so let me try to
illustrate the the the core idea of uh
diffusion models and it's it's it's a
very elegant and beautiful idea and it
goes back to ideas in uh in sort of
probability and in physics nearly 100
years ago there is this uh this idea
called uh there was someone called Paul
lanah and they are the so-called
stochastic lanan models and that's
that's really the intellectual root of
this idea but let me explain to it much
in a much more pragmatic sort of a way
uh what are we after we are after a
generative model of images right so
that's our goal so how do we get now a
neural network is a function so if you
give a neural network one input it's
always going to give you one output so
if I want to get a
distribution how how can I get it I
can't right a neural network always
gives you one output for one input so
the only way to get a distribution over
a set of images is that the input also
must be a
distribution so for example the input
could be uh a gaussian noise right so in
this case if you see on the extreme
right there is a gaussian noise image
where every pixel is a sample from a
gaussian so what we can do is we can
generate uh samples of gaussian noise
that's very easy to do and then this
neural network the so-called generator
model what we do with that is we feed it
these different inputs which are
different realizations of this gaussian
noise model and then we'll get different
outputs and those different outputs what
we want them to be is over the set of
possible uh real world images so you
might get cats or dogs or people or
chairs or bicycles or what have
you so our job is to train this neural
network which when given as an input
some noise image outputs one of
uh the set of possible images and
essentially according to the probability
distribution over the set of all images
is the idea clear I mean just interrupt
and ask me questions if you if this is
uh if what I'm saying is not clear
because okay so that's what we are
trying to
do and and that's been the goal for a
while so for example these variational
autoencoders vaes that's how they they
trained in a particular way but the way
you use them is that you input noise and
then the output is uh is is uh is a
sample and because you will input
different noise samples the output will
be different samples of
images okay now how does how do these
diffusion models work so in diffusion
models the idea is that uh we take uh we
are going to have a so-called forward
diffusion process and a reverse
uh at a reverse denoising process so the
forward process goes something like this
I mean it's very easy to see in this
picture so we are going to have some
image like uh this image of this cat and
we keep adding noise to
it okay and we keep scaling the original
signal down so you are trying to keep
the energy the same but you you keep
scaling down the original signal and you
keep adding noise so it becomes more and
more noisy and eventually it's like uh
not distinguishable from noise in some
way so but you do it in a series of
steps so maybe you do it in 1,000 steps
I mean in this figure it's like seven
steps but it could be over like a th
steps okay and now uh uh and what do we
what do we train a neural network to do
we train a neural network to go in the
reverse Direction so the forward
Direction is easy right it's just adding
noise now what we will try to train in
is a neural network which can do the
reverse denoising process so the neural
network what it is trying to do is given
one of these
images it's Target is to get to that
denoised
image and you know the Target right
because we generated this example so we
took this original image and we added
noise and then we went all the way to
this thing which looks pretty much like
noise and what we are doing is we are
driving the process backwards which is
to go from noise to to this image of
this uh this cat or is it a dog I'm not
sure okay so uh so that's the and then
so you train a model for doing that and
this model can and of course you will
give it lots and lots of example uh such
sequences so you might start with an
image of a dog or a cat or a person or a
bicycle or a chair and each of them goes
through this SE this sequence by which
it noise is added and it eventually
becomes Pure Noise and then uh you've
got like a a training uh training data
set because for this sequence you know
what your reverse denoising process has
to do it has to get back to the original
image and so we train that model and we
train model with many many examples of
images images of cats images of dogs
images of chairs and so forth and then
at test time so that's the training
process at test time the idea is you
just feed it a noisy image a noise which
you just syn I mean you just uh you can
sample from a gaussian distribution and
then and then you let it go with this
neural network which is going to
generate these do a series of these
denoising steps and then you'll get
something you might get a chair you
might get a cat you might get a
dog okay so that's the intuition and
uh uh so so now let's get more
mathematical about this the formal
definition of the forward process is
that uh that's Illustrated here so let's
look at the math so there is so this is
a mark of chain you start from some
initial State x0 then you go to X1 X2 so
on and and this x subt is basically an
image which is uh indistinguishable from
noise what are you doing at each stage
you're adding gaussian noise and uh that
is indicated by this uh this process so
what is this this notation n n is for uh
normal
distribution uh right so the normal
distribu uh so there's the distribution
of the V random variable X subt it it
has how do I specify a normal
distribution I specify a mean and a uh
covariance right so the mean is XT minus
one so you start from you start for
every pixel from the uh from the uh the
previous stage okay you scale it down a
little bit by the square root of 1 minus
beta T and then you add noise okay so
this is the variance here the variance
of this gaussian and it's add diagonal
matrix with this uh with every entry in
the diagonal being this beta subt so
your every pixel is being
independently so with every to every
pixel you're independently adding a
little bit of
noise and uh uh so so that's what you're
doing here and you do that to get from
x0 to X1 X1 to x2x and so
forth okay and then the the
concatenation of this processes is is
what you get it at the end now note an
observation because we are dealing with
gaussians here if you add a bunch of
gaussians that's also a gaussian right
so gaussians have this very nice
composition property and this is going
to be helpful to
us okay uh so this is the forward
diffusion process and then if you crank
through the algebra with these square
root of one minus betas and so forth I
mean that's what you get these these
terms but this is not important you can
work through that it's the intuition is
pretty clear that your each of them is a
little gaussian but if you think of a
big step it's like a big gaussian but
it's always gaussians all the
way so what's going to happen
essentially the addition of noise is
losing
structure right so you can start out
with some initial data and as you are
adding noise over time it's going to
become something like a look start to
look like a gausia right this should be
intuitive okay uh and now what you're
going to do is uh you're going to learn
to go backwards let me see if I have a
picture which illustrates this
better
uh actually I want to give you one
intuition which is very cool which is uh
that
uh uh why are we doing this breaking up
into small steps
and it's to do with if you think of
physics right so Suppose there is some
liquid and uh at the end of the lecture
I'll show you some video and you drop
some colored fluid in a liquid then over
time what happens is that it diffuses
and then it becomes
uniform so so there is some initial
structure and then it's getting lost
over time as diffusion proceeds we're
doing something similar here about the
images now uh can we go backwards right
this sounds crazy right okay but it
sounds crazy but if you consider a small
step going backwards is not unreasonable
because if you think about physics in
the at any small
scale all the processes of neonian
mechanics are
reversible right over a long time frame
entropy increases but locally over a
very small moment of time the processes
are
reversible okay so this is somehow this
I find this intuition very comforting
that the that the the long step of going
from signal to noise if is is not so
easily reversible but a micro step like
the step from X2 to X3 is adding a
little bit of noise so we might hope to
recover the going from X3 to
X2 and and this is kind of an intuition
which actually can be made quite quite
formally precise with this whole theory
of laima
Dynamics okay so where are we going here
uh so
uh okay let me I'll show you okay so
this is another fun video I found and
let me play this and so these are the
there are there is this genre of people
who put up videos on YouTube which is
explaining the con same concept at
multiple different levels of explanation
so so uh so I'll let uh play this video
and just the first two levels of
explanation are not bad let's learn
about the fusion models the fusion
models are a fairly new innovation in
the world of deep learning they are
generative models that are being used in
many different domains like audio
generation or image generation you might
have heard of them with their use in Del
or imagin for example diffusion models
can be used Standalone like they did
with glide or it can be used as part of
a bigger and more complex model like it
was done with Del 2 very recently their
inner workings are quite complex so it
could get a little bit confusing to
understand how they work and how they
are trained that's why in this video we
are going to approach it step by step
and explain the fusion models in five
varying levels of difficulty starting
from the easiest one to the more complex
one level one the fusion models were
inspired by non-equilibrium
thermodynamics from physics and as you
can understand from the name this field
deals with systems that are not in
thermodynamic equilibrium for example a
drop of paint in a glass of water the
density of the paint after you just
dropped it is very high in one spot and
zero in other parts of the Water by the
laws of physics the drop Will diffuse
into the water until it reaches an
equilibrium in the physical world
reversing this diffusion process is
simply not possible but with diffusion
models the goal is to learn a model that
can reverse this process and bring the
drop of paint to its original state in
other words the drop being in one spot
includes some information and as the
diffusion process progresses we lose
information in our case this information
equals to clear images so working
backwards from this diffused paint is
equivalent to working backwards to a
proper Image level two
diffusion models work by replicating
this diffusion process by adding noise
to original images and later learning
how to reverse this noise process the
noise is applied to the images following
a micro chain what is a micro chain a
micro chain is a chain of events where
the current time step only depends on
the previous time step so that means
there are no cross- dependencies between
time steps that do not immediately
follow each other and this Assumption of
markco chains makes it tractable for the
noise adding to be reversed later so at
the end a diffusion model is a Markel
chain where in each time step we add a
little bit of noise to our image until
the image only consists of noise and
later learning how to reverse this noise
adding process after it is trained given
only noise this model is able to
generate high resolution images level
three so now that we understand what
diffusion models do is basically add
noise to an image let's understand what
it means to add noise to an image there
are many different types of noise and
the noise that is added in the fusion
models is called the Gan noise what is
gsan noise it is a noise that has the
probability distribution of a gan or
normal distribution given the different
mean and variation values for
this yeah I I'll stop this here because
uh you know about cin noise you don't
need to learn that from her uh let me
see if I can quit here we have to stop
share
again the location and the width of the
distribution e
okay so uh maybe that uh water droplet
picture was helpful uh so where were we
uh so now uh what we what we are going
to train our neural network to do is uh
is basically this reverse denoising
process and uh uh okay what's the
connection here uh if you want to
understand this theoretically what is
going on here what's this what is being
optimized you really have to to go back
to these VA variational
autoencoders I have a reference for that
in the slide deck but I'm not going to
go into
it and uh where are we here I'm going to
skip all this uh the the
final even though the the theoretical
understanding is a bit complicated the
Practical aspects of our intuition is
very clear I think what you're training
is this denoising network Network which
given an image gets you to a slightly
less noisy version of the image and this
network here is H so there's algorithm
one and algorithm 2 so algorithm one
let's look at that this is for training
time so you have uh uh some so this
Epsilon Network starts out being one
which uh just has is a gaussian and what
you're doing in this training step is
essentially training this denoising so
you're trying to uh okay and then at the
sampling time you're going to start from
uh synthesiz first you'll generate some
so why you get different samples is
because you get different inputs so you
get different inputs which are these
samples from a gaussian uh distribution
and then you run it through this
sequence of denoising steps and these
steps because they had different inputs
they will land up going to different end
points and these different endpoints
will then look like different
images uh how you implement this so this
is there's a lot of low earlier work
used to be done with convolutional
networks uh unet were very popular today
like everything else everybody is using
Transformers and in the diffusion policy
paper they they say that they started
out with uh convet and then later on
switch to to
Transformers uh okay there's a detail on
how you add the noise and how many
stages so here there's a practical
consideration when you are trying to use
this for a robot policy so note that
you're doing all these steps of den
noising
at at uh in real time so your robot is
trying to move and you're trying to
figure out what are the next steps and
to do that uh you have to be running
this uh several steps of denoising so
therefore you can't really afford to do
a thousand of these steps you have to do
a relatively small number and it has to
be working really fast so uh so if you
read the the paper from uh shuran song's
group you will see uh that they managed
to make all these details work out so
you are you're trying to do uh inference
in like 0 2 seconds or something like
that so that get and you you you output
a sequence of actions so you can start
to execute those and then you have some
time in the meanwhile to be
uh you know running this uh this
inference again and and so
forth uh what happens to the image okay
this is also a maybe a helpful thing
that uh in the forward diffusion process
essentially the higher information high
frequency information gets killed first
and then gradually it gets to the low uh
the low uh frequency
information
okay uh and then the den noising process
you can see that in the beginning so
this is the den noising starts from the
noise and goes to the to this generating
the sample and uh so what's happening is
that initially the low frequency content
starts to appear and then later on the
high frequency content appears so there
are a variety of papers playing off on
this theme so it's almost the papers
which are suggesting that you can think
of it as an auto regressive process
where initially the low frequency
content is produced and then the the
medium frequency content is produced
conditioned on the low frequency content
and then the and then finally The High
Frequency content is
produced uh connection to V yeah there
is uh Theory there but I would get into
uh but uh uh I'll probably uh leave it
here
uh okay conditional diffusion models
okay so conditional diffusion models in
the context of image synthesis the
conditioning is very often on
text so so these are examples so uh so
the there's the text a photo of Aon
wearing an astronaut helmet looking out
of the window at night and uh and then
this is the image which is synthesized
so in the context of diffusion policy
for robotics what is our uh what is the
condition going to be on so the
conditioning is going to be on on
whatever is the uh the the observation
so the observation could be propri
setion it could be camera
input uh and then uh here are varieties
of
tasks conditional okay so the way how do
we include conditions in the diffusion
models so basically you have the
standard uh forward process reverse
process in the reverse process you have
the C so the C is what you conditioning
on and uh the uh the uh what we'll see
is for the diffusion policy the C is
going to be the
observation okay I think I'll end
here and uh let me uh stop share and
maybe